<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aws on pipetail Blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.pipetail.io/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aws on pipetail Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2020 pipetail. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 07:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.pipetail.io/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>10 most common mistakes using kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-05-04-most-common-mistakes-k8s/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-05-04-most-common-mistakes-k8s/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had the chance to see quite a bit of clusters in our years of experience with kubernetes (both managed and unmanaged - on GCP, AWS and Azure), and we see some mistakes being repeated. No shame in that, we’ve done most of these too!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll try to show the ones we see very often and talk a bit about how to fix them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More EKS tips to make your life easier</title>
      <link>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-04-13-more-eks-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-04-13-more-eks-tips/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of the last month on implementing EKS. Surprisingly, we&amp;rsquo;re always solving the same concerns no matter what project we&amp;rsquo;re working on. Here&amp;rsquo;s couple of tips for your EKS clusters!
Skip kube2iam, go directly with IAM Roles for Service Accounts Kube2iam is amazing tool. I really like it and it helped me with granular control access in couple of projects. However, there&amp;rsquo;s a better solution that is supported out of the box: IAM roles for services accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with PodSecurityPolicy on EKS</title>
      <link>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-03-15-psp-on-eks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Mar 2020 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-03-15-psp-on-eks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you might already know, security is not something that a specialized department should
be responsible for. Instead, we all should bear in mind that security matters and build
secure solutions from the very beginning. Today we&amp;rsquo;re gonna talk about some practices
in the world of containerized apps and Kubernetess. So let&amp;rsquo;s say we have some best practices
for the containerized workloads. But how to enforce that? We&amp;rsquo;ll tell you right away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GitLab Runner on EKS</title>
      <link>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-03-05-gitlab-runner-on-eks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-03-05-gitlab-runner-on-eks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GitLab-CI/CD is a great and powerful product for CI/CD pipelines. Hosted gitlab.com solution offers shared runners and some usage minutes based on your paid plan (even if the free tier). Though you might want to run your own runner in your private or public cloud. I will show how to run GitLab runner on AWS using terraform, Elastic Kubernetes Service and GitLab kubernetes integration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Systems Manager Session Manager: bye bye bastion hosts!</title>
      <link>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-02-24-amazon-ssm-session-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2020 07:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-02-24-amazon-ssm-session-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are customers where public internet access is no go. But
at the same time you need to access your EC2 instances,
right? How would you approach this? Usually, we use bastion hosts,
that&amp;rsquo;s basically a different name for jump host you can use
to access internal resources. In AWS, you don&amp;rsquo;t need to manage
such extra instances and take care of all the low-level configuration.
Instead, you can leverage fully managed Session Manager from the
AWS Systems Manager suite!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More complicated EKS scenarios: EKS managed worker nodes without internet access</title>
      <link>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-02-12-eks-private-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2020 08:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.pipetail.io/posts/2020-02-12-eks-private-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you using EKS managed worker
pools? If you don&amp;rsquo;t have any specific reasons for not using them, you should.
It saves tons of time plus it boosts the &amp;ldquo;managed Kubernetes&amp;rdquo; feeling.
However, this pretty new offering did not cover one specific use case:
cluster with no Internet access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>